[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
prentist tasa Advanced Training as you
all know I've already published 46
YouTube videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts from past couple of videos have
started posting the real time
scenarios where you might encounter an
obstacle while automating the test cases
so how can we solve different types of
obstacles in real time so this is
our lesson five as part of real time
scenarios with obstacles please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos and don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a realtime scenario where you
encounter an obstacle you need to
interact with complex web tables and
rows are Dynamic within the web table
which means the data within the cells
are Dynamic and the web table is complex
to interact so how can we
solve this obstacle while automating
your test cases so for that let us first
understand what is the obstacle that we
are going to solve
for so here we're going to
solve the fifth
obstacle here 922 4 8 so let's go for
it so let us understand what is the
obstacle so here complete table
interactions click the edit button for
John do so it might looks like simple
but let me explain so this particular
obstacle is categorized as hard why
because if You observe closely here here
this is our web table with columns first
name last name email and
action so in this web table we can see
around four
rows we need to click on edit button for
the row where first name is
John and the last name is do that means
this is first R John do is in first room
row you need to click on
edit but so as soon as you click on edit
so let me try again one more time what
happens the page gets refresh if you see
here now where is joho now the joho is
in the last
R let's click on edit again and let me
try again now your joho is in second
row okay so that means the data within
the rows is dynamic so now how can I
click on edit
button corresponding to the John do
row so for that let us go to
prenta as usual we're going to
start scanning the application and the
objects so what is the folder this is
the folder that we are working on
obstacles is the folder double click on
this so we already completed four
different
obstacles in our previous lessons so I
would recommend you guys to go through
those obstacles so now let's right click
on obstacles
folder and click on scan and select
application so this is the application
that I would like to
scan now let us maximize the
window and if you see here what is the
table this is your web table that we are
talking about this is your web table
persons is the web table right so let's
select
this and click on highlight see it is
highlighting the web table that means
this is our web table and if you see for
every row you have two buttons one is
remove another one is edit correct so
that's why we can see remove edit remove
edit so four rows four remove edit
buttons okay so let me select one edit
button because we have to click on edit
button I would like to select one of the
edit button so we need not to select
multiple but one of the edit button if
you see the edit button is not uniquely
identified
because you have multiple edit buttons
and the properties of those buttons are
same for now you need not to worry about
the edit button not identifying uniquely
we are going to solve this unique
identification while automating our test
case so for now you can just ignore even
though it is not not identifying
uniquely let's save the objects so what
I did I've selected web table and one
edit button so let's rename this module
as I told you it's best practice to
rename the
module with logical sense okay I'm
renaming it with obstacle name okay so
now let's save
and close your X
scan so let's go back to trient tasa so
this is our new fifth obstacle where I
can
see web table row column and edit button
so now let's create a new test case
right click on this obstacle folder and
click on create test
case name this as obstacle
okay double click on test case so now
let us create a test case so we need to
automate the test case to automate you
need to drag this module whatever we
captured and drop onto your test
case Okay so once drag and drop onto the
test case now let's see what we should
do okay so if you see here the web table
has row column and edit button so
basically the edit button is outside the
row and column whereas in the
application the edit button is within
the row so that's why we have to bring
this inside a row so that this edit
button can be uniquely identified so
earlier when I am saving the module
this edit button was not uniquely
identified because it is not within the
row so what I'm going to do now for that
let's go back to your module what I'm
going to do this is your edit
button I want
to move this edit button to the row
inside the row simply click on this
drag and drop
inside
row so now you can see your edit button
is inside
row you have a cell and row correct in
the same way now your test case also you
can see here you have table row cell
edit button so if you add remove button
you will have a remove button also okay
so now your edit button can be uniquely
identified whatever the row number which
I pass that becomes your edit button so
now here under cell I would like to
select first
name why because I would like to click
on an edit button which has a first name
of
John so that means I selected
the row as first name and if You observe
closely I'm not mentioning the row
whether it is a first row second row
last row or something because I want to
iterate through all the rows identify if
it is a John then click on edit button
okay so for that what I'm going to
do first name if first name what is the
value John
here I'm not going to verify I'm going
to use the action mode as
constraint If You observe closely
here I'm selecting a table select a
table and then I'm selecting a
row I'm validating first name
John and I'm including it as a
constraint constraint means filter so
basically check for the
row which has a first name as John
constraint means it is going to look for
that particular row and then if you see
here in the first name I can see this is
John and this is also John that means I
have a duplication right but last name
should be do here the other one has last
name little so now I need to include a
constraint for last name also so that's
why I'm going to select here another
cell if the Cell last
name
contains do John do d e do and add a
constraint constraint means it's going
to look for this
data then only it proceeds to The Next
Step Okay so under this table for any
row because I'm not selecting first row
or second row okay for any row look for
first name as John and look for last
name as dove that's why I'm including
action mode as constraint and then if
these two matches then click on edit
button here clicking on edit button I
can pass X or I can pass click I would
like to pass click so that you can see
the mouse
cursor it is clicking on which row okay
so done so now let's save the test
case so let me repeat what we did
okay we are selecting a
table and then I'm
selecting a row also but but when I'm
selecting a row I'm not specifying any
row number here and then I'm looking out
for first name I'm looking out for first
name column this is your column for
first name column look for JW that is my
constraint action mode and then for last
name column look for do that is my
constraint if these two constraint
matches then click on edit
button right so now let's mark the work
state as
completed save your test case so let me
run the test case now let's run this
test case and see what happens right
click and run in
scratchbook see it went to second row it
clicked you solve this automation
problem let me do one thing let me try
again let's see here now your joho is in
third row let's run this particular test
case one more time and see what happens
right click and
run see it is clicking on edit button
which is in third row so you solve this
automation problem so this is how you
can solve an
obstacle where you need to interact with
the complex web tables and the data
within the web table cells is a dynamic
in nature if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries hope you all
understand how can we solve for an abst
ccle where you need to interact with the
complex web
tables in which the data within the
cells is dynamic in nature while
automating your test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos and don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]